I'm building an AI business from scratch
and I'm putting every single step of it
on this channel the good
the bad the ugly
this is day one and in this video
I'm basically gonna be breaking down my first AI
workflow that can take any YouTube channel
and turn every video into clean transcript data
before I show you how it works
here's why transcript data is actually useful
in the first place
the first obvious use case is um
market research
if your customers are already watching YouTube
to learn about your space
those videos are already basically full of language
they already understand problems
objections examples
promises mistakes
questions
and that can all be used to feed
your offers your landing pages
sales scripts ads
Faqs
all of it
the second use case is turning a company's
own videos into assets so if you've got webinars
tutorials demo
training videos or interviews
transcripts
can let you turn that into something like a
searchable knowledge base
like support docs
email sequences internal SOP's
or even something like context for an AI assistant
in my use case it's a version of the first one
I'm using it to study what's already working in AI
content
see what people keep repeating
and what nobody's really showing
and that's basically how I landed
on the angle for the channel
uh showing the whole process
of building the business from scratch
alright so
I'm gonna give you a quick overview
of the tools that we need to use
and how the transcript system works
and we'll jump right into it
so you're gonna go to YouTube
select all the videos from any YouTube channel
that you wanna transcribe
and then you're gonna paste them into a Google sheet
which will then have to uh
make sure we get a clean list of URLs
because it's gonna be a bit messy
and we're gonna have to sort it out
we're gonna then
proceed to download a tool from a Github
that helps us transcribe everything
the way YouTube works it it has auto captions
every video has already been transcribed
and this tool just lets you download
all those transcriptions
we're gonna run in our terminal
we're gonna have to create a pipe and code
we're gonna use the Chat GPT desktop app to help us
it's just literally one click away at any time
you can take a screenshot
you can
bump it into the chat and just say hey
I'm stuck
you know and it will help you
you can also just do it in the web version
it's just gonna be more annoying
but you can definitely do it
in terms of what the output will look like
we'll get a text file with um
all the video transcriptions
and we can also get a few like
stats and metrics about the video if we want to
the output will look something like this
we'll have the creator's name
and then we have some information about the video
we have some stats we have the URL
video duration views
likes and pretty much any data that this uh
YT DLP tool can pull out
um you can download it from Github
but you can also just run a command in your terminal
get it downloaded
have it run the
um Python code
that would then
transcribe all the YouTube videos and get them in a
nice text file for us
uh we're gonna run most of the stuff locally
so we're gonna try
we're gonna create a transcript system folder
and then inside that folder
we're gonna have three other folders
an input folder
an output folder and a tools folder
in the input folder
this is where we're gonna add our CSV
with the URLs that we take from YouTube
and we're just gonna name it like Alex Mosey dot CSV
um we'll just take him as an example
everybody knows him
he's just a legend so output folder
this is where we get the actual text file
we don't need to add anything inside this folder
and tools this is where we download that y
t d
L P
tool from Github
with that said let's jump into it
alright so let's go to YouTube
Alex
go to his videos
and we're just gonna select all his videos
by the way you can do this with any YouTube channel
and you can do it with like 10:20 all at once
if you want
once you have the system in place
it's pretty easy to
transcribe anything you want
you're gonna copy this now when you paste this
this will be a bit messy
we're gonna open a Google sheet
and paste it in column A
well as you can see
this is a bit messy so we wanna clean this up
um you can go to extension and go to app script
and then we're gonna ask Chat
GPT to give us a code that would actually like
clean this up for us
we're gonna delete the placeholder here
and we're just gonna open chat
I'm gonna say
hey chat can you please help me put together an app
script code that will clean up all the URLs
in column A
everything that's in there now is um hyperlinks
so I want to pull out the actual link from the text
and have it nice and clean
in column a
everything that is not a URL
delete it
keep it all the same size all the same colour
and um
just make it neat also
add a action button that will let me render this code
anytime I want to in my menu
I'm gonna send that off to chat
and it's gonna give us a code
there we go
the fact that it's so quick
like it just blows my mind every time
we're gonna copy that code
we're gonna paste in here
and we're gonna hit save
now it might not work perfectly the first time
you just take a screenshot
you paste the code you ask it
what's the problem
and I'll usually tell you how to fix it
it might take one or two iterations
and then you have the code running
you hit run
you then have to review permission
and then you hit continue
and you can see now you have a tools button right
that wasn't here before so you hit this tools button
and you hit clean URL in column a
you see the script is running
you already hit URLs here
see now this is not what we wanted
it deleted all of them
so I think it couldn't identify that those text
um that we had there were actual URLs
so we're gonna just gonna say hey chat
you just deleted everything
make sure you actually pull out the link from those
texts
this hyperlinks attached to those texts in column a
so please don't delete everything
pull those and fix your code
thanks
I'm just gonna paste it in there
and we're gonna save it and then we're gonna hit run
there we go see
every single link is now nice and clean
let's see how many we have
we got 502 videos
now we're gonna hit file
download CSV and then you're gonna name it Alex Amazon
now we need to set up the folder structure
everything we'll do will be on our desktop
we're gonna run it in our terminal
we're gonna create a new folder and we're gonna name it
uh
transcribe system
beside this transcribe folder
we're gonna add three folders
an input folder
we're gonna have an output folder
this is where our actual transcripts will be added to
this is where they will populate
and then we'll have a tools folder
this is where we download the Github tool that I
told you about so now what you're gonna do
you're gonna right click this folder
and you're gonna hit new terminal
this will open up a new terminal
and you're gonna go to chat
and just say
hey chat thanks for the abstract code that worked
can you now please
help me install the Github tool called
y t d
L P
just give me the
command that I need to run in my terminal
thanks
so you see it will give you a command
and then I come on to check if it's working
you're gonna hit that and you can see it's downloading
and boom should be downloaded
and now we're gonna check if it's downloaded properly
by just hitting the next command
and
it should tell us which version has been downloaded
it might take a couple seconds
there you go 20
26 0 3 17
it should be downloaded
we can also check the folder here and you can see y
t d
L P
this is the tool that we just downloaded
now that that's done
you're gonna ask Chat GPT to generate a Python file
so first thing you're gonna wanna create the file
then you're gonna paste the code inside it
open the terminal and you're gonna say
hey chat can you please
give me a command that will create a Python file
inside my terminal
I want it to be a text edit file
so then I can save it and add my Python
code to run the system
there you go so we gave you this code
you just gonna run it inside the terminal
and boom it just open up a text edit file
where we can drop the code
now we're gonna generate the code
that will do all of this for us
we generate it once
and then it can run forever with a very simple command
so we're gonna ask chat
hey chat can you now help me generate the Python code
for my YouTube transcript system
the folder structure goes like this
there's an input folder
where the CSV file goes from every YouTube creator
there's an output photo
where I want my text files to populate
I want them to be named after the creator
name underscore transcript
and I want you to make sure that if the YouTube
captions are inaccurate
where there's a lot of duplicates
or a lot of phrases that have been repeated
or haven't been downloaded properly
check that text make sure it's all nice and clean
so what this tool does
if you don't really tell it to check those transcripts
it would uh
just run a lot of duplicates
cause that's what it downloaded from YouTube
um
and there will be sentences that have been said twice
or three times in a row
and then you move to the next one
it's just cause there's a
like a glitch when you download it
so you have to
tell the code to check for those duplicate sentences
and it'll do it for you now
you're gonna copy that code
and you're just gonna paste it in here and uh
hit save
so hit command s to save it and then close this
now what you should see in your toast folder
now you also have a Python file
which we can now run anytime we wanna run the system
so now that's all set up let's test how this works
we're now gonna take the CSV file that we downloaded
and we're gonna add it to the input folder
Alex and Ozzy CSB
and um
now what we're gonna do is open it
terminal and then you're gonna paste it here
alright so right now uh
it's saying no CSV file found
so you'll bump into stuff like this
but when you do you just tell chat
hey chat um
I'm getting an error inside the terminal that says
no CSV file found
I'm not sure why that is
because my file is already inside the input folder
is there any reason in particular
did I miss any file name did I spell incorrectly
or what do you think the reasons could be
also a cool thing
you can always give it access to your terminal
and then you'll see what the error is
alright so you see
saying I have a similar folder
that might be spelled slightly differently
so we're gonna I think it's
I might have a space at the end or something
let's check rename
I think we have a little space here you see
alright
so let's try run it again so we're gonna scroll up
and we're gonna copy and we're gonna run it again
processing one of 501
this um
is probably gonna take a few minutes
but you can let it run in the background
and the cool thing is you just
you can just come back and it will be transcribed
another thing to note
you can add as many as you'd like
inside the input folder
you don't need to run this command
again for each single one
if you have 10 here
this command that you just ran now
will transcribe all of them
so you can go to YouTube
and you can search whatever creator
you'd like
hey Jack
can you give me 10 URLs of uh
the best AI creators
and then you can just open these up and then look at
look at what's working look at what's not
and take what's good and avoid what's bad
you can analyze hooks you can do
whatever you want with that content
there are people that have figured out
what you wanna do
and so why don't you just learn from them
learn from their mistakes
so obviously you're not gonna take it to like
absolutely copycat them
um because you can't you
you will never beat anybody at being them
you only beat them at being you
you use them for reference
because these people that are ahead of you
you look at okay
this guy's doing this he's his hook is like this
he's
and then you can take that info
and well do what you will
um but this is how you run the system
alright so it's now finished
it's been probably more than 60 minutes now
I'm halfway through editing the
the video we just we just made
but that's a good thing about it
you can let it run in the background
you get back to it and 500 transcripts done
now let's take a look at the output
we're gonna go to our folder
in the output folder
and then you can see Alexa Mosey transcript
this was the saved file
now we're gonna open up and this is what it looks like
we got video one
you got the date you got the title
the URL
duration of the video 36 minutes um 47,000 views
1,600 likes
you just go for it
and you see the entire video transcript
now
I haven't read for it word for word
but I think it's about 80 to 90% accurate
you can check everything if you want
I personally didn't go through all of it
you can go ahead and check if you like
and one more thing to mention is that
once you have your Python code
you don't need to redo this every single time you do it
the only command that you ran is um
is actually the the very short one
this command here in your terminal
and this will just
go through and run that code
that is saved in that file
every time a new CSV file is detected inside this
input folder
it would um
transcribe it and
it would skip
the ones that has already been transcribed
but make sure you mention that when you build a code
that's how it works
and
I hope you found it helpful